A Guide to the Papers of the Page and Walker Families 1742-1886
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Page and Walker Families 1742-1886
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3098
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited by Miss Anne Page of Newport News, Virginia, on 1949 February 10. It was purchased by the library on 1975 May 1.
Scope and Content
Papers of Thomas Walker, his son Francis, and other family members contain accounts, receipts, slave bills of sale, legal papers & correspondence regarding debts & estate settlement comprise the bulk of the collection. There are a variety of plats and surveys, land patents and indentures for Louisa and Albemarle Co., Va. property, including a survey of the Castle Hill estate, 1816 and Keswick, 1865. Many items pertain either to the Loyal Land Co. (1750s) or to the Albemarle Iron Works.
Of special interest are copies of treaties, 1744 and 1752, with the Six Nations at Lancaster and Logstown, and a sale of 6 million acres in Ohio in 1777 to George Croghan transferred to Walker.
Among the correspondence and miscellaneous papers are a letter protesting the Stamp Act; a letter re the location of the Albemarle County Court; an account with George Washington, 1763; accounts at the Eagle Tavern; an undated plan of Charlottesville; an 1801 letter discussing sickly people of Kentucky; an 1802 Valentine's day poem by Samuel Mitchell; a letter from John Marshall, discussing legal problems in a slave sale; a Revolutionary soldier's pension claims; a plea for William Wirt to Francis Walker to settle an estate for educational funds for James Gilmer; a letter from James Monroe re a survey of the Tennessee boundary; a list, ca. 1830, of polite literature for a young lady; a midshipman's appointment signed by Andrew Jackson; 1850 letters describing Uncle Tom's Cabin, and hazing at V.M.I.; testimonies to secure a Civil War medical discharge; a letter from an ex-slave describing the murder of Richmond editor Henry Rives Pollard; and 5 newspapers and an almanac, 1799-1864.
Correspondents and legal parties include Nicholas Cabell, William H. Cabell, W. O. Callis, Edward Carter, George Croghan, Robert Dinwiddie, Francis Fauquier, John Murray, 4th earl of Dunmore, Charles Everett, Joshua Fry, Ira Garrett, George Gilmer, Peachey Ridgway Gilmer, Sir William Gooch, Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Lewis, Fielding Lewis, Benjamin Lincoln, Reuben Lindsay, Peter Lyons, Matthew Maury, Nicholas Meriwether, James Monroe, Mann Page, R.C.M. Page, Louis Philippe Albert d'Orleans, comte de Paris, D. M. Randolph, Judith Page Walker Rives, Alexander Spotswood, Francis Walker, William Wirt, and James Wood.
Contents List
- Letter, Nicholas Meriwether to Thomas Walker 1742 June 13 (Box 1)
- Manuscript copy of the Treaty of Lancaster 1744 July 2 (Box 1)
- Land grant (Louisa land), William Gooch to James Hanegan 1747 August 20 (Box 1)
- Charles Barret to Dr. [Thomas] Walker re [Loyal Company?] 1749 December 7 (Box 1)
- Bond 100 pound note, Nichloas Meriwether to John Lewis 1751 June 3 (Box 1)
- Letter, J. Moore to Thomas Walker re Loyal Company 1752 April 29 (Box 1)
- Manuscript copy of Treaty of Logstown 1752 June 13 (Box 1)
- John Meriwether to James Power re committee of the Loyal Company to act for Company. 1752 July 2 (Box 1)
- Fielding Lewis to James Power re committee of the Loyal Company 1752 July 22 (Box 1)
- Thomas Walker, contract with Joshua Fry to buy any of Fry's Loyal Company lands remaining unsold 1753 February 17 (Box 1)
- John Syme to Mrs. Walker re tobacco shipment 1755 June 5 (Box 1)
- Robert Dinwiddie to Daniel Design. Land grant in Louisa County 1756 August 16 (Box 1)
- Thomas Walker, survey of his tract in Louisa County 1759 September 20 (Box 1)
- John Syme to Mrs. Walker re tobacco shipment 1755 June 5 (Box 1)
- Robert Dinwiddie to Daniel Design. Land grant in Louisa County 1756 August 16 (Box 1)
- Thomas Walker, survey of his tract in Louisa County 1759 September 20 (Box 1)
- Blank printed conract for survey of the Loyal Company [1760] (Box 1)
- Robert Jackson to Thomas Walker re Messers Champe & Hunter 1761 August 5 (Box 1)
- B. Grymes to Thomas Walker. Receipt on Capt. Philip Buckner's account 1761 (Box 1)
- N. Walthoe Clerk of the Council, Order adjourning Albemarle Court to home of Stephen Hughes 1761 December 9 (Box 1)
- Letter, Francis Fauquier to "Mr. Commissary Walker," re location of Albemarle County Court 1762 March 6 (Box 1)
- Indenture, Richard Randolph and Anne Randolph to Thomas Walker for 240 acres in Albemarle County 1762 June 12 (Box 1)
- Account of Dr. Thomas Walker with Richard Randolph 1762 December 20 (Box 1)
- Account of Dr. Thomas Walker with George Washington 1763 May 2 - 1766 November (Box 1)
- Indenture, Richard Haggard to Thomas Walker for 300 acres in Albemarle County 1763 October 4 (Box 1)
- Indenture, Robert Lewis to Thomas Walker for 435 acres in Albemarle 1763 September 9 (Box 1)
- Promissory note, Thomas Walker to Andrew Lewis 1763 December 28 (Box 1)
- Letter, John Thornton to Dr. Thomas Walker re debt 1764 April 9 (Box 1)
- Letter, David Ross to Thomas Walker, re lots in Charlottesville 1765 October 11 (Box 1)
  Wants deed immediately so he will not have to pay stamp tax
- Accounts of the Ablemarle Iron Works 1766-1792 (Box 1)
  Ablemarle Iron Works
- Andrew Lewis. Schedule of lands purchased from Thomas Walker 1766 June 24 (Box 1)
- Indenture, Patrick Fisher to Thomas Walker 1766 October 8 (Box 1)
- 35 items concerning Albemarle Iron Works 1766-1805 (Box 1)
- John Norton of London to Thomas Walker 17[67] March 31 (Box 1)
- Indenture, John Moore and Mary Moore to Thomas Walker, 560 acres in Albemarle County 1767 September 11 (Box 1)
- Col. Syme to Thomas Walker 1767 December 21 (Box 1)
  Albemarle Iron Works
- Joseph Phillips and John Phillips to Thomas Walker 1768 February 22 (Box 1)
- Thomas Walker v. Anderson and Timberlake in Louisa County Court, judgement for the plaintiff 1768 October 10 (Box 1)
- Alexander Spotswood to ?, re executions against his estate 1769 July 1, ALS (Box 1)
- Mortgage for furniture of livestock, Benjamin Bramham to Thomas Walker 1769 July 28 (Box 1)
- Articles of Agreement between William Cabell, Edward Carter, Thomas Walker, etc. 1770 December 28 (Box 1)
- Account of David Bunch of Louisa with Dr. Thomas Walker 1771-1779 (Box 1)
- Account of the Albemarle Iron Works with Alexander Trent 1771 February - 1772 May (Box 1)
- Articles of agreement between Edward Carter and John Old 1771 September 21 (Box 1)
- Inventory of goods at the [Ablemarle] Furnace 1772 (Box 1)
- W.J. Waddell to Thomas Walker 1772 January 16, ALS (Box 1)
- Land grant, Lord Dunmore to Thomas Walker for 226 acres in Albemarle County 1772 August 1 (Box 1)
- Peterfield Trent to [Thomas Walker] 1772 August 11, ALS (Box 1)
- Survey of tract for "John Wilkinson and Company" 1773 November 6 (Box 1)
- Receipt, William Penn to Thomas Walker 1773 December 27 (Box 1)
- John Wilkinson to Thomas Walker 1774 June 28, ALS (Box 1)
- Account of estate of C. Duke with Thomas Walker 1774 July 18 (Box 1)
- John Wilkinson to Thomas Walker 1774 August 7, ALS (Box 1)
- Account, Thomas Walker with George Divers 1774 August 16 - December 15 (Box 1)
- Edward Carter to Thomas Walker, Jr. 1775 May 31, ALS (Box 1)
- Indenture, various Indian chiefs to George Croghan 6,000,000 acres on the Ohio River (attested copy) 1775 July 10 (Box 1)
- Articles of agreement between John Olds and Thomas Walker 1777 April 1 (Box 1)
- Indenture, George Croghan to Thos. Walker, et al., lands on the Ohio (original and typed copy) 1777 July 30 (Box 1)
- Land grant, Thomas Jefferson to Thomas Walker 1780 July 20 (Box 1)
- Thomas Walker's account with James Bunch for medical services 1780-1786 (Box 1)
- Articles of agreement between Thomas Walker & Eliz. Thornton for their marriage 1781 January 7 (Box 1)
- Francis Walker, militia comission as ensign, signed by Jefferson 1781 May 27 (Box 1)
- Benjamin Lincoln, discharge of Joseph Newman from the First Virginia Regiment 1783 July 28 (Box 1)
- Thomas Jefferson, account with Thomas Walker 1783 October - 1794 September (Box 1)
- Bill of sale for Negro slave family sold by David Hooper to Thos. Walker 1785 December 14 (Box 1)
- Papers regarding pension claims of Charles Witt, 5 pieces 1783 - 1796 (Box 1)
- Indenture for "Surls," Albemarle County, Thomas Walker to Francis Walker 1786 April 10 (Box 1)
- Power of attorney, Thomas Walker to Francis Walker 1786 April 12 (Box 1)
- Bill of sale for Negro, Samuel G. Cabell to Patrick Davis 1786 June 27 (Box 1)
- Judgement of the Louisa County Court for the plaintiff, Thomas Walker v. Nathan Gibson 1786 November (Box 1)
- Letter, John Marshall to Dr. Thomas Walker 1789 July 9 (Box 1)
- Papers in the case of Walker vs. Cabell, et al. 1790-1804 (Box 1)
- John Marshall to the High Court of Chancery. Plea on behalf of Walker [1790], Albemarle Iron Works (Box 1)
- Albemarle County Court order to Thomas Walker, Francis Walker, et al., for road work 1790 June (Box 1)
- Thomas Walker, account with John Walker 1790 September 16 (Box 1)
- Statement of Nicholas Cabell and others in case of Walker vs. Cabell, etc. 1790 December 5 (Box 1)
- Letter, Thomas Martin to Col. John Walker 1791 July 6 (Box 1)
- Thomas Walker, account with Nicholas Lewis 1792 October 7 (Box 1)
- John Marshall to Francis Walker 1793 February 23, ALS (Box 1)
- Indenture for 2500 acres in Albemarle County, Thomas Walker to Francis Walker 1793 November 16 (Box 1)
- Letter, Oliver Clevland to Francis Walker [1793-1795] (Box 1)
- Account of Francis Bowcock wtih Francis Walker, 2 pieces 1794-1804 (Box 1)
- Letter, Robert Pollard to Francis Walker 1796 December 7 (Box 1)
- Receipt, John H. Oswald to Col. Thomas Bell and Capt. William Meriwether 1794 December 31 (Box 1)
- Receipt, T. Meriweather to Francis Walker 1796 December 7 (Box 1)
- Inventory of the estate of Dr. Thomas Walker, copy 1796 (Box 1)
- Daniel Ockerman's receipts for wheat to Francis Walker (13 pieces) 1796-1797 (Box 1)
- Jason Bowcock to Francis Bowcock, account and promissory notes, 3 pieces 1798-1802 (Box 1)
- Peachy R. Gilmer to Francis Walker 1798 January 6 (Box 1)
- Peachy R. Gilmer to Francis Walker 1798 January 10 (Box 1)
- Land grant, for 48 acres in Albemarle County, Gov. James Wood to Thomas Walker [Jr.] 1798 April 18 (Box 1)
- Promissory note, Charles B. Hunton to Daniel Ockerman 1798 August 4 (Box 1)
- 2 land grants for land in Albemarle County, Gov. James Wood to Francis Walker 1799 August 8 (Box 1)
- Major Francis Walker, account with James Lindsay 1799-1800 (Box 1)
- Francis Walker, account with Brown, Rives and Company 1799-1800 (Box 1)
- Thomas Walker, Bill at the Eagle Tavern [17??] March 18 (Box 1)
- Unidentified plat of [tract purchased by Thomas Walker] [17??] (Box 1)
- [Plan of Charlottesville] [17??] (Box 1)
- Letter (fragment), John Thornton to John Lewis [17??] (Box 1)
- James Brown to [Francis Walker] [ca. 1800] (Box 1)
- Hugh [Nelson] to Francis Walker [1800] (Box 1)
- Letter, Weston Alcock to Francis Walker [ca. 1800] (Box 1)
- Account of Col. Francis Walker with Robert Gamble and Son [1800] (Box 1)
- Letter, G[eorge] Gilmer to Francis Walker re T. Divers 1801 March 1 (Box 2)
- John Wilkinson to Col. Francis Walker 1800 March 9, ALS (Box 1)
- Letter, Ch[arle]s Everett to Col. Francis Walker re Kentucky and its sickly people 1801 June 14 (Box 2)
- Letter, Francis Preston to Francis Walker re "the Company" and its agency 1801 August 26 (Box 2)
- Letter, Martin Mims to Col. Francis Walker re arms for Albemarle militia 1801 August 29 (Box 1)
- Letter, John Walker to Francis Walker re slaves 1801 October 24 (Box 1)
- Francis Walker, account at Eagle Tavern, Richmond, 3 pieces 1801-1804 (Box 2)
- Letter, L. and N. Bramham to Col. F[rancis] Walker re money 1802 April 6 (Box 1)
- John Wilkinson to Francis Walker 1802 April 23, ALS (Box 2)
- Note, Charles Anderson to Francis Walker re corn 1802 May 13 (Box 2)
- Letter and bill, Thomas Taylor to Francis Walker for rum 1802 June 6 (Box 2)
- Account, F. Cowherd to Francis Walker, with various endorsements 1802 June 17 (Box 2)
- Letter, George Fox to Col. Francis Walker re a carriage he had built for Walker 1802 June 23 (Box 2)
- Letter, Robert Hoskins to Francis Walker re a debt 1802 July 1 (Box 2)
- Letter, Thomas Taylor to Col. Francis Walker re payment for rum. 1802 August 25 (Box 2)
- Letter, Charles Anderson to Col. Francis Walker re rent for a mill 1802 August 26 (Box 2)
- Letter, James Monroe to Col. Francis Walker re Thomas Walker's survey of Tennessee boundary 1802 August 28 (Box 2)
- Letter, J. Shipman to Maj. Francis Walker re a possible suit re a survey 1802 September 2 (Box 2)
- Note, Cha[rles] B. Hunton to Francis Walker re purchase of a mill 1802 September 4 (Box 2)
- Note, James Lindsay to Col. Francis Walker re money 1802 September 4 (Box 2)
- Letter, Henry Bowyer to Francis Walker re a debt of William Russell 1802 September 10 (Box 2)
- Letter, Martin Dawson to Col. Francis Walker requesting payment of a debt 1802 September 10 (Box 2)
- Letter, John Browne to Captain Francis Walker re his father's estate and debts, with an enclosed account 1802 September 10 (Box 2)
- Letter, D[avid] M[eade] Randolph to Francis Walker re debts 1802 September 15 (Box 2)
- Richard Anderson, William Brown & Company to Col. Francis Walker re debt 1802 September 17 (Box 2)
- Letter, William Wirt to Francis Walker re James Gilmer's estate 1802 September 19 (Box 2)
- Letter and account, D[avid] M[eade] Randolph to Francis Walker 1802 October 14 (Box 2)
- Letter, Henry C. Coleman to Francis Walker re a debt 1802 November 29 (Box 2)
- Letter, Lewis Johnston to Francis Walker, re a debt, and trees Walker has cut 1802 December 31 (Box 2)
- Letter, Thomas Hunton to Col. Francis Walker stating he cannot pay debt at present 1803 (Box 2)
- Letter, Lewis Johnston to Francis Walker re interest on a debt 1803 January 3 (Box 2)
- Letter, James Lindsey to Francis Walker re rental of a slave wagon driver 1803 February 4 (Box 2)
- Letter, Francis Nelson to Francis Walker re sale of a horse, and of a watch 1803 February 7 (Box 2)
- Peter Tinsley, Clerk of High Court of Chancery, blank summons in case of Thomas Walker's estate 1803 March 1 (Box 2)
- Letter, O. Towles to Col. Francis Walker re dismissal of several law suits 1803 March 11 (Box 2)
- Letter, George Gilmer to Francis Walker re a debt of Mr. Davis' to him 1803 March 14 (Box 2)
- Note, R. Gambell to Col. Francis Walker re his account with the Milton post office 1803 April 8 (Box 2)
- W[illiam] Harvie to Francis Walker re a debt of the "old Company" 1803 April 13 (Box 2)
- Letter, Lewis Johnston to Francis Walker re debts 1803 April 22 (Box 2)
- Letter, John Mayte to Francis Walker re the latter's whiskey order 1803 April 27 (Box 2)
- Note, W[illliam] Nelson to Col. Francis Walker re a "plank" 1803 April 28 (Box 2)
- Letter, Lt. Col. Francis Walker to Lt. Joseph Goodman ordering a court martial 1803 May 10 (Box 2)
- N[imrod] Bramham to Francis Walker re availability of "Superior quaity" flour 1803 May 20 (Box 2)
- Note, James Lindsay to Francis Walker re a shipment of "goods" 1803 May 27 (Box 2)
- Letter, John Minor to Francis Walker re a "Bill of Injunction" 1803 May 27 (Box 2)
- Letter, M. Walker to Col. Walker re business 1803 July 1 (Box 2)
- Letter, W. Alcock to [Francis Walker] offering to rent a "plantation at Cobham" 1803 July 25 (Box 2)
- Letter, James Maxwell to Francis Walker re a debt 1803 October 22 (Box 2)
- Letter, Reuben Herndon to F[rancis] Walker, W.D. Davis, and W.W. Cooper re loan of a "horse cart" 1803 August 19 (Box 2)
- Letter, Marbell Camden for William Galt to Col. Francis Walker re load for cart 1803 November 18 (Box 2)
- Note, Nimrod Bramham and Company to Francis Walker re $200 payment to Benjamin Herring 1803 November 22 (Box 2)
- Letter, Reuben Herndon to Francis Walker refusing to "accomodate" him until Mr. Bramham's return 1803 December 7 (Box 2)
- Letter, Nath[aniel] Quarles to Capt. Francis Walker re a debt 1803 December 26 (Box 2)
- Note and account, Flem[in]g Turner to Col. Francis Walker re goods purchased 1803 December 29 (Box 2)
- Letter, Reuben Mansfield to Col. Francis Walker re settlement of an account 1804 January 17 (Box 2)
- E. Massey's certificate concerning Mr. Mansfield 1804 February 4 (Box 2)
- Letter, E. Moore to Francis Walker stating his inability to send Walker money 1804 February 3 (Box 2)
- Letter, Jason Bowcock to [Francis Walker], re his retirement as an agent 1804 February 7 (Box 2)
- Letter, Patrick Michie to Col F[rancis] Walker re a debt of Chapman Johnson's 1804 February 8 (Box 2)
- Letter, Char[les] B. Hunton to Col. Frank Walker re a debt 1804 February 11 (Box 2)
- Letter, Matthew Maury to Col. Francis Walker asking him to return borrowed salt 1804 February 14 (Box 2)
- Letter, R.H. Waller to Francis Walker re a Deed of Trust of H. Nelson 1804 March 20 (Box 2)
- Note and account, Will[iam] Temple to Francis Walker re paint 1804 April 23 (Box 2)
- Survey of tract in Albemarle County for Francis Walker by William Woods 1804 May 1 (Box 1)
- Receipt for tobacco inspection, Williamson and Frankle[?] to William Sebery 1804 May 22 (Box 2)
- Note and accounts, Robert Gamble and Son to Col. Francis Walker re goods 1804 May 22, (2 pieces) (Box 2)
- Note, Peter Lyons to Francis Walker re payment of his Loyal Company claim 1804 May 25 (Box 2)
- Letter, N. Taylor to Francis Walker re $35 debt 1804 June 19 (Box 2)
- Letter, E. Page to Francis Walker re $100 debt 1804 June 24 (Box 2)
- William H. Cabell to Col. Francis Walker 1804 November 20, ALS (Box 2)
- Dr. [Samuel] Mitchell's Valentine's Day Poem, 1802 February 14, Copied on listed date 1804 November 28 (Box 2)
- William H. Cabell to [Francis Walker] 1804 November 29, ALS (Box 2)
- John Wilkinson, et al, to Francis Walker 1805 February 15, ALS (Box 2)
- Francis Walker to Thomas Walker Maury, Power of Attorney 1805 February 28, ALS (Box 2)
- Letter R[euben] Lindsay to Francis Walker re a meeting about a debt 1805 March 10 (Box 2)
- Letter, James Henderson to [Francis Walker] re payment of a debt 1805 June 20 (Box 2)
- Comission of Jacob C. Clarke as Lt. in Militia 1805 July 13 (Box 2)
- Letter, Francis Walker to Thos. Rutherford re 2 wagon loads of wheat (retained copy) 1805 October 13 (Box 2)
- Receipt for wheat, John Gordon (for Thomas Rutherford) to Francis Walker 1805 October 17 (Box 2)
- Peter Tinsley, Clerk of the Superior Court of Chancery, summons to examine witnesses in case of Weston Alcock v. F. Walker 1805 October 22 (Box 2)
- Letter, James B. Gilmer to Francis Walker re a debt 1812 July 22 (Box 2)
- John Peyton to Francis Walker re a debt of Charles B. Hunton 1813 October 12 (Box 2)
- Survey of Castle Hill estate, by William Woods, showing 3775 acres in Albemarle and Louisa 1816 (Box 2)
- "A course of polite literature for a young lady" ca. 1830 (Box 2)
- Comission of William C. Bannister as Midshipman signed by Andrew Jackson 1832 February 20 (Box 2)
- Letter, R.W.T. Gwathmey to Dr. Mann Page 1832 July 3 (Box 2)
- Letter, John C. Page to Dr. Mann Page re family news, tobacco sales, wheat 1842 July 9 (Box 2)
- Samuel Gilmore Cattell to Thomas Page [child's letter to friend] 1842 December 19 (Box 2)
- Assessment of land, slaves, etc., in Albemarle County for 1848, by Ira Garrett, Clerk 1849 January 3 (Box 2)
- Note for $100, Mann Page to Richard Gambrill 1849 July 1 (Box 2)
- Bond for $500, Mann Page to Richard Gambrill 1850 April 16 (Box 2)
- Letter, W. Lefebre Durufle to William Cabell Rives (copy in French) 1851-1852 (Box 2)
- Cotelle to [William Cabell Rives] (copy in French) 1852 June 1 (Box 2)
- Letter, William Wilmer Page to Mrs. Jane Y. Page, re his plebe experiences at VMI 1852 July 26 (Box 2)
- Survey of tract by George C. Dickinson (copy by T[homas] W[alker] P[age]) 1862 February (Box 2)
- Letter, Judith Page Rives to Mrs. J.F. Page, chiefly family news from Paris, but mentions Uncle Tom's Cabin1852 June 23 (Box 2)
- Documents related to military service of Thomas Walker Page 1864, (2 pieces) (Box 2)
- Map of Keswick, property of Thos. W. and R.C.M. Page 1865 October (Box 2)
- Deed for land in Ablemarle, Thomas W. Page to R.C.M. Page 1865 October 18 (Box 2)
- Plat of Keswick Plantation for Dr. Mann Page ca. 1865 (Box 2)
- Contract for sale of stock, implements, and houses on Keswick farm, R.C.M. Page and Thomas W. Page 1866 July 2 (Box 2)
- Appointment of Thomas Walker Page as surveyor of Albemarle roads 1866 July 2 (Box 2)
- Letter from a former slave describing assassination of H.R. Pollard [1868] November 26 (Box 2)
- Plat of 150 acres belonging to Mrs. J. Page 1870 April 8 (Box 2)
- Letter and bill, A.S. Perkins to Thomas Walker Page re land survey 1870 May 7 (Box 2)
- Note, J.B. Madison to Thomas W. Page covering a survey (not present) 1871 March 4 (Box 2)
- Mann Page, record of payment for lots 1871 October 1 (Box 2)
- Survey, Thomas Walker Page to [?] Bragg 1872 March 27 (Box 2)
- Letter, Philippe, Comte de Paris to Dr. Richard Channing Moore Page re his historical writing (with envelope) 1886 January 9 (Box 2)
- Letter, A.F. Taylor to Dr. [Mann?] Page, Keswick [18??] March 2 (Box 2)
- Farm notes n.d. (Box 2)
- P[eachy] Gilmer to Col. [Francis] Walker n.d. (Box 2)
- Niles' Weekly Register, Baltimore, October 28, 1826 and May 30, 1829 (Box 2)
- The Va. Gazette and General Advertiser, Richmond, January 25, 1799 (Box 2)
- The Enquirer, Richmond, November 14 1809 (Box 2)
- The Daily Chronicle, Charlottesville, September 24, 1864 (Box 2)
- Richardson's Va and NC Almanac for 1864, Wynne's Edition (Box 2)